Guide to the Indivisible: Stories of American Community Records, 1999-2002 RL.10139
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1999-2002; 4; 20 boxes
  - Danny Lyon (United States, b. 1942), Building on the Border, 10
    - A historic marker for the spot "where American blood was shed on American soil," along with murals from Mission, and the Farm Workers Union hall in Pharr, 1999 (Box 29, Item (L2000:009:002))
      In 1847 Congressman Abraham Lincoln declared that "the spot" was not, nor never had been part of Texas or the United States, and therefore could not justify an invasion of Mexico. This unpopular sentiment ruined his political career for the next decade.
    - A farm worker, Rolando Garcia, sings into an onion, with the bus schedule out of McAllen, 1999 (Box 40, Item (L2000:009:003))
    - Homes and interiors at Colonia Jessups with Lauro Perez preparing lunch at the Proyecto Azteca site, 1999 (Box 40, Item (L2000:009:004))
    - Maria Lopez at home in a colonia near Alamo, Texas, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:001))
    - At the All Valley Flea Market Dance, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:003))
    - Martha Rangel harvesting onions near Mercedes. Ms. Rangel carries her immigration papers in her back pocket in case she has to show them to INS workers, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:004))
    - Aristeo Orta, a construction worker at Proyecto Azteca, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:002))
    - Noe Galindo, Colonia Jessups, near Monte Alto, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:005))
    - Farm worker in a field near Monte Alto, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:006))
    - The dance hall, All Valley Flea Market, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:007))
    - Epifanio Morales at Proyecto Azteca, 1999 (Box 41, Item (L2000:033:008))
    - Taco stand, downtown McAllen, 1999 (Box 28, Item (L2000:033:009))
    - Roberto Rodriguez's family near Edinburg, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:010))
    - Pay phone, San Juan, Texas, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:011))
    - Family at the flea market, Pharr, Texas, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:012))
    - Farm worker, a regular at the All Valley Flea Market dance, cutting cabbage, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:013))
    - At the All Valley Flea Market Dance, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:014))
    - Farmers clear an onion field near Monte Alto, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:015))
    - Route 281, the Military Highway, 1999 (Box 27, Item (L2000:033:016))
      The horizon shows the Rio Grande River, established as the border with Mexico after the War of 1848.
  - Sylvia Plachy (United States, b. 1943, Hungary), 11
    Fourteen 16x20 and 20x24" gelatin silver prints documenting the training and work of community doulas and midwives in Ithaca, N.Y., and the families who benefit from their support before, during, and after childbirth.
    - Jacqueline Shepard and another student in their doula class train for labor support through role-playing, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:001)
    - Doula Jacqueline Shepard caring for Sunshin Gordon, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:002))
    - Jacqueline Shepard in her brother's backyard holds up portraits of her role models, her mother and her sister, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:003))
    - Lise Golub, at a postpartum visit, delights in Olivia Gordon, a baby whose birth she recently attended as a doula mentor, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:004))
    - Robert Gordon holds his new baby, Olivia, before she is taken to the nursery, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:005))
    - Olivia studies her father, Robert Gordon, minutes after being born, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:006))
    - Sunshin, Robert and Olivia Gordon pose for their first formal family portrait, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:007))
    - Jane Arnold, midwife, attends Sunshin and Robert Gordon hours before the birth of their first child, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:008))
    - Robert Gordon holds Sunshin as first-time doula Jacqueline Shepard adds support, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:009))
    - Sunshin Gordon resting between contractions, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:010))
    - Robert attending to Sunshin Gordon during a wave of pain, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:011))
    - Sunshin Gordon is comforted by the hands of midwife Jane Arnold and doula Jacqueline Shepard, 1999 (Box 39, Item (L2000:034:012))
    - Robert and Sunshin Gordon hold their new firstborn, Olivia, 1999 (Box 33, Item (L2000:034:013))
    - Jane Arnold, midwife, hands Sunshin and Robert Gordon their new baby, Olivia, 1999 (Box 33, Item (L2000:034:014))
  - Eli Reed (United States, b. 1946), 12
    Eighteen 16x20" framed gelatin silver prints of community volunteers and their friends in Eau Claire, South Carolina.
    - Leroy Moss, a community worker and activist who is blind, at the recreational center that is named in his honor, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:001))
    - Reverend Wiley Cooper teaching children about the many portrayals of Jesus, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:002))
    - Scott Trent Jr., former president of the Eau Claire Community Council, looking at graffiti on the Norfolk-Southern railroad trestle on North Main Street, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:003))
    - Henry Hopkins, local organizer and executive director of the Eau Claire Community council, at a meeting on the prevention of violence, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:004))
    - An Eau Claire street at dusk, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:005))
    - Rhett Anders, current Eau Claire Community Council president and real estate agent, in front of a historic local property, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:006))
    - Fran Potter, a member of the zoning board and former president of the Eau Claire Community Council (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:007))
    - Reverend Wylie Cooper of Shalom and volunteers help rehabilitate the home of an elderly resident, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:008))
    - Lee Bolton and a Shalom member do yard work as part of their housing rehabilitation effort with the Eau Claire Community of Shalom, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:009))
    - Church members at Wesley United Methodist Church prior to a baptism service, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:010))
    - Rotary Club Meeting, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:011))
    - Toliver's Mane Event barbershop, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:012))
    - Men's Breakfast Group leaving College Place United Methodist Church, where they have met for over fifty years, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:013))
    - A local senior artist hands a bouquet she made to a visitor, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:014))
    - The South Carolina National Guard participates in a local parade in an Eau Claire neighborhood, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:015))
    - Playing baseball at a trailer park on Fairfield Road, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:016))
    - Columbia chief of police Charles Austin, Sr. baptizes Brandon Hawkins at Central Baptist Church, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:017))
    - Scott Trent Jr. has lived in the same house in Eau Claire for nineteen years, 1999 (Box 31, Item (L2000:031:018))
- Project Files, 1988-2002; 3
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access note. Some materials in this series are electronic records that require special equipment. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Logs (Box 1)
  - Tape lists (Box 1)
  - Tape lists (Box 2)
  - Postcards (Box 2)
  - Tape lists and transcripts for Delray Beach, Village of Arts and Humanities, Handmade in America, and Proyecto Azteca (Box 3)
  - Tape lists (Box 4)
  - Tape lists and transcripts for Alaska Fishing Communities, and folders of project information for Eau Claire, Handmade in America, Proyecto Azteca, Southwest Youth Collaborative, Village of Arts and Humanities, and Yaak Valley (Box 5)
  - Fact-checking and captions files (Box 5)
  - Tom Rankin files (Box 5)
  - Check-list (Box 5)
  - Postcard captions (Box 5)
  - Book bios (Box 5)
  - Possible volunteers (Box 5)
  - Site-specific concerns (Box 5)
  - Library materials (Box 5)
  - Getting started (Box 5)
  - CHALK (Calif.) transcripts (Box 6)
  - Doula transcripts (Box 6)
  - Dine Bi Iina transcripts (Navajo Nation) (Box 6)
  - Fact checking files (Box 6)
  - Possible community activist sites (Box 6)
  - Give Back: files on process of finding local archives sites after each project (Box 6)
  - Pew Charitable Trust files (Box 7)
  - Radio project/program for Village of Arts and Humanities (Box 7)
  - Project background (Box 7)
  - Guides for educators (Box 7)
  - Tom Rankin files (Box 7)
  - Publicity files (correspondence, resumes, radio programs, proposals, press releases) (Box 7)
  - Give Back (files on finding local archive sites after each project) (Box 8)
  - Video: Talking Cloths: Making Art and Making Community: Village of Arts and Humanity (VHS), 2002 (Box 8)
  - Tape logs and transcripts for Alaska Fishing Communities (Box 9)
  - Community archives files (correspondence, offer letters) (Box 9)
  - Project feedback (Box 10)
  - Zip disk with scanned images of headshots (content of slides?) (Box 10)
  - Press coverage files (Box 10)
  - Tape logs and transcripts for Delray Beach, Handmade in America, Yaak Valley, Eau Claire, Village of Arts and Humanities, and Dine Bi Iina (Navajo Nation) (Box 10)
  - Tape logs and transcripts (Box 11)
  - Publicity files (Box 11)
  - NEA grant file and other grant information (Box 12)
  - Center for Creative Photography file (Box 12)
  - Conferences (Box 12)
  - Contracts and other exhibit files (Box 12)
  - Forms and facts (Box 12)
  - Pew Charitable Trusts files (Box 12)
  - Village of Arts and Humanities project files (captions, articles) (Box 12)
  - Southwest Youth Collaborative (Box 13)
  - Yaak Valley Forest Council (Box 13)
  - Daniel Rothenberg (Box 13)
  - Jeff Whetstone (Box 13)
  - Dan Collison (Box 13)
  - Slides: 35mm color images taken during project; images include portraits of community individuals, of photographers, and other scenes (Box 14)
  - Documentary photographer and interviewer biographies and other information such as publicity, photographers' past project, and some correspondence (Box 14)
  - Slides: 35mm color images arranged by photographer, and exhibit installation shots (Box 14-A)
  - Photographer biographies (cont.) (Box 15)
  - Doula project transcripts (Box 15)
  - Comprehensive files on Doula, Eau Claire, and Navajo projects (field notes, articles, captions, supporting materials for projects) (Box 15)
  - Comprehensive files on Alternatives Credit Union, Handmade in America, Delray Beach, Citizens on Patrol, and CHALK projects (field notes, articles, captions, supporting materials for projects) (Box 16)
  - Comprehensive files on Alaska Fishing Communities and Proyecto Azteca projects (field notes, articles, captions, supporting materials for projects) (Box 17)
  - CDs of contemporary popular Hispanic music (unopened) (Box 17)
  - Proyecto Azteca (NM) transcripts (Box 17)
  - Press packet for Indivisible (Box 17)
  - Tape logs (no transcripts) for all project locations (Box 18)
  - Proyecto Azteca transcripts (Box 18)
  - Outreach, exhibit files (Box 18)
  - Postcard exhibit (Box 18)
  - Launch money (Box 18)
  - Travel (Box 18)
  - VIP lists (invitees) (Box 18)
  - Transcripts (Box 23)
  - Transcripts (Box 25)
  - Field notes (Box 25)
  - CHALK 14, 16, 1999; 10 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0001)
    Contains document files.
  - CHALK 13, 1999; 5 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0002)
  - CHALK 12; CHALK 4, 1999; 3 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0003)
  - CHALK 11, 1999; 1 file; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0004)
    Contains a document file.
  - CHALK 9, 1999; 2 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0005)
  - CHALK 8, 1999; 1 file; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0006)
  - CHALK 5, 1999; 4 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0007)
  - Proyecto Azteca – Group at PA, 1999; Approximately 10 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0008)
  - CCP Doula, 1999; 4 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0009)
  - Alaska; Dine bi iina, 1999; 8 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0010)
  - Proyecto Azteca; Dine bi iina 4, 1999; 2 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0011)
  - YAAK Transcripts, 2001; 16 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0012)
  - YAAK Transcripts (in mac format), 1999-2001; 5 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0013)
  - Village Transcripts (in mac format), 1999-2001; 14 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0014)
  - Village Transcripts, 2001; 24 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0015)
  - SWYC Transcripts (in mac format), 1999-2001; 7 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0016)
  - SWYC Transcripts, 2001; 10 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0017)
  - Proyecto Azteca Transcripts (mac), 1999-2001; 17 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0018)
  - Proyecto Azteca Transcripts, 2001; 14 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0019)
  - Handmade Transcripts (in mac format), 2001-2001; 8 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0020)
  - Handmade Transcripts, 2001; 18 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0021)
  - Eau Claire Transcripts (in mac format), 2001; 26 files; 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0022)
  - Eau Claire Transcripts, 2001; 9 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0023)
  - Doula Transcripts (in mac format), 2001; 2 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0024)
  - Doula Transcripts, 2001; 9 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0025)
  - Dine Bi Iina Transcripts (in mac format), 2001; 12 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0026)
  - Dine Bi Iina Transcripts, 2001; 4 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0027)
  - Delray Transcripts (in mac format), 2001; 11 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0028)
  - Delray Transcripts, 2001; 9 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0029)
  - CHALK Transcripts (in mac format), 2001; 8 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0030)
  - CHALK Transcripts, 2001; 15 files; 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0031)
  - Credit Union Transcripts (in Mac format), 2001; 7 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0032)
  - Alternative Credit Union Transcripts, 2001; 33 files; 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0033)
  - Alaska Transcripts (in mac format), 2001; 20 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0034)
  - Alaska Transcripts, 2001; 38 files; less than 1 megabyte. (Digital-materials RL10139-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box Run 17, Disk RL10139-FL3-0035)